<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>www.hrishikeshballal.net</title>
    <link href="https://www.hrishikeshballal.net/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://www.hrishikeshballal.net" />
    <updated>1970-01-01T01:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Hrishikesh Ballal</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.hrishikeshballal.net</id>

    <entry>
        <title>About</title>
        <author>
            <name>Hrishikesh Ballal</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.hrishikeshballal.net/about.html"/>
        <id>https://www.hrishikeshballal.net/about.html</id>

        <updated>2020-08-17T10:32:34+01:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    I am Hrishikesh Ballal, welcome to my website. I have had this site in one form or the other for the past 25 years or so. In real life, everyone calls me Hrishi. The H is silent so it is pronounced as ‘Reeshee’. My name,&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://www.hrishikeshballal.net/media/posts/1/photo_2018-04-25_21-32-46-bw.jpg" sizes="(min-width: 61.3125em) 50vw, 100vw" srcset="https://www.hrishikeshballal.net/media/posts/1/responsive/photo_2018-04-25_21-32-46-bw-xs.jpg 300w ,https://www.hrishikeshballal.net/media/posts/1/responsive/photo_2018-04-25_21-32-46-bw-sm.jpg 480w ,https://www.hrishikeshballal.net/media/posts/1/responsive/photo_2018-04-25_21-32-46-bw-md.jpg 768w"  alt="" width="446" height="380"></figure>
<p>I am Hrishikesh Ballal, welcome to my website. I have had this site in one form or the other for the past 25 years or so. In real life, everyone calls me Hrishi. The H is silent so it is pronounced as ‘Reeshee’. My name, ऋषिकेश in Devanagari / Marathi has a Sanskrit origin. <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rishikesh">Rishikesh</a> is also the name of a ancient city in the foothills of the Himalayas. This site provides Atom or RSS feeds and you can subscribe to them to get the latest. I am <a href="http://www.twitter.com/hrishiballal">@hrishiballal</a> on Twitter and also on <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/hrishiballal">LinkedIn</a> and <a href="https://www.github.com/hrishiballal/">Github</a>.</p>
<p>I am Mechanical Engineer by training specializing in Engineering Design, Operations Research with degrees from <a href="http://www.umich.edu/">University of Michigan</a> and <a href="http://www.mit.edu/">MIT</a>. In 2015, I completed my PhD at the <a href="http://www.bartlett.ucl.ac.uk/casa">Centre for Advanced Spatial Analysis</a> at University College London with a focus on geodesign. My thesis was around early stage design and is entitled <a href="http://discovery.ucl.ac.uk/1471177/">Collaborative planning with digital design synthesis</a>.</p>
<p>I have built and work on three things: Geoforage.io, Geodesignhub.com and Openskies.sh.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.geoforage.io/">Geoforage.io</a> is a spatial data collection product primarily used in the context of public engagement. We provide services to understand the preferences and capture the knowledge of a space directly from citizens and other people who use it. In addition to enabling these “geo-surveys” we host your spatial data, analyze it and help you understand the location you are working on.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.geodesignhub.com/">Geodesignhub.com</a> provides software for mediation and negotiations about difficult social political problems around a space. In addition to enabling negotiations using our technology, we provide project organization and management support around implementation of the negotiated outcomes.</p>
<p><a href="https://openskies.sh/">Openskies.sh</a> is a open source software company to support current and future aerial robotics ecosystem. My focus is on drone registration and “bringing drone registries online”. Specifically, I work on Identity and Authentication and API harmonization for drone operations. I also work with different stakeholders around regulatory aspects of unmanned aviation and its integration with national and international airspace.</p>
<p>My expertise and work in the “geo” domain has a strong mechanical / systems engineering focus. I am a founding member the local chapter of OSGEO: <a href="https://wiki.osgeo.org/wiki/Ireland">OSGeo Ireland</a> and a huge advocate of open data for governance and public policy. I feel like I have had many lives professionally. I have written a huge amount of closed and open source software, worked in the automotive industry, United Nations, spent time in Japan, worked at Microsoft among other things. Prior to my “geo” focus, I was working as a regulatory expert on the hardware aspects of consumer electronics. It all started when I was offered a fellowship to work on solving the collection and end-of-life aspects of e-waste and it was the thesis for my <a href="http://dspace.mit.edu/handle/1721.1/47866">degree</a>.</p>
<p>All content in this site is licensed under the <a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</a>. Unless otherwise stated, everything here is © 1996 ~ 2020 Hrishikesh Ballal.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
